Siddhant Saxena

565 West Amaryllis Drive Bloomington, IN 47404 | +1-812-361-2943 | sidsaxen@umail.iu.edu LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/siddhant-saxena-a0151799

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Data Science enthusiast on a mission to help organizations derive insights out of raw numbers and create value. I specialize in Statistical Data Analysis and Predictive Modelling and have keen interest in visualizing information.

EDUCATION

Indiana University, School of Informatics and Computing

Bloomington, Indiana

Master of Science in Data Science

May 2018

Uttar Pradesh Technical University

Noida, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

January 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Courses: High Dimensional Data Analysis, Exploratory Data Analysis, Applied Machine Learning, Data Mining,

Data Analysis and Modelling, Information Retrieval **Languages**: R, Python, SQL, Java

Data Visualization: R (ggplot2, lattice),Python(Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly),Tableau, Gephi **Statistical Analysis**: Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, Advanced Hypothesis testing

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Web Application: ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Yelp Dataset Challenge

October 2017-December 2017

- Built a Recommendation System to recommend top restaurants to Yelp users using a hybrid of different Memory based Collaborative filtering.
- Trained a model to predict multiple categories for a business using random forest classifier for Yelp Dataset Challenge.

Stock Market Prediction using news article

April 2017

• Examined the effects of news articles on the movement of the stock market. Used sentiment analysis and n-gram models to predict a binary output variable-rise or fall in the DJIA value

Insurance Claim Severity Prediction

August 2016 - December 2016

• Trained a regression classifier over masked insurance claim data having about 189,000 labeled records with 163 categorical and numeric variables and implemented various feature extraction and feature selection techniques to improve mean absolute error while predicting the cost and hence the severity of insurance claim on the test set

Analysis of Large Text Corpora

November 2016

• Analyzed books like 'Les Miserables' and '12 Years a Slave' to quantify the strength between characters using Gephi, an information Visualization tool and Natural Language processing techniques through a Python Script

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Risk Management Solutions

Newark, California

Risk Solutions Intern

June 2017 – August 2017

• Developed front end of Accounts and Jobs modules and a part of Accumulations module for Risk Browser Version 18 using frameworks like CoffeeScript. ReactJS, NodeJS frameworks.

Infosys Limited Bengaluru, India

System Engineer, Knowledge Management (KM) Group

December 2014 – March 2016

- Developed front end of an E-learning application to provide an online learning platform for 0.2 million Infosys employees leading to an increase in overall knowledge sharing by 20%
- Designed and developed management system for Konnect, a social networking platform for knowledge sharing using backend technologies like C# and MS SQL Server along with frontend technologies like Angular JS framework; major automation of processes reduced information overload of admin by 60% (Awarded Technical Champion award)

LEADERSHIP

Data Science Club

Bloomington, Indiana

February 2017-Present

- Vice President, Founding Member
- Working towards the vision of creating a strong and united Data Science Community for IUB. Goals include extending meaningful membership in the club and helping us establish deep industrial partnership.
- Committed towards continuous innovation, process improvement and ensuring use of best practices in every task.